자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
안에 안 계시니까
제가 받을게요
He's not there.
I'll take it.
리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감님께
To CAPTAIN LELAND STOTTLEMEYER
MONK Season 4 Epi. 9
Mr. Monk and the Secret Santa
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
진현경(jhk8012@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
김웅식(lx403dm@nate.com)
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/12/02
어이, 테리
Terry, hey.
그거 똑바르지가 않은데
왼쪽이 너무 낮아
That's not straight.
The left side's too low.
- 이 정도면 괜찮은데요
- 아니
- It's good enough.
- No, it's not.
- 몽크가 온단 말이야
- 이런, 제길
- Adrian Monk is coming.
- Oh, hell.
알겠습니다
Okay.
- 경감님
- 어
Captain. / Yeah.
사모님께서 전화하셨는데
I took a message.
Your wife called.
어머니가 많이 편찮으셔서
오늘 밤 참석 못할 거라고 하셨어요
She said her mother's sick
and she won't be able to make it tonight.
장모님이...
Her mother's...
저런, 그것 참 안됐네
Well, that's too bad.
그리고 이건 결재하셔야 할
다음 주 근무자 명단입니다
And these are the duty roasters for
next week. You have to sign them.
고맙네, 앨리스
Thank you, Alice.
오늘 파티 기대되나?
You looking forward to
our little party?
그런 것 같네요
I guess so.
보통 몇 시까지 파티를 하죠?
How late do these
things usually go?
작년에 아내와 내가 자리를 뜬 게
새벽 2시 30분이었지
Last year, Karen and I left
at about 2:30 a.m.
그리고 테리 경사는
그때도 테이블 위에 서서
And Terry, Detective Chasen
was still standing on a table
팬티만 입고 'Help me, Rhonda'를
스페인 어로 부르고 있었다네
(Help me Rhonda : Beach Boys의 곡)
in his boxer shorts singing
'Help me, Rhonda' in Spanish.
거짓말 마십쇼
전 스페인 어를 할 줄 모릅니다
That's a lie.
I don't speak Spanish.
- 아냐, 아주 잘해
- 참, 경감님 앞으로 온 겁니다
- Oh, yes, you do.
- Oh, and this came for you.
누가 접수처에 두고 갔대요
Someone dropped it off
the front desk.
리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감님께
Captain Leland Stottlemeyer.
수고하십니다, 스토틀마이어 경감님
이스트우드 자동차 용품점
Captain Stottlemeyer, thank you
for your business, Eastwood Auto Supply.
이게 뭔지 아나, 앨리스?
바로 뇌물이야
You know what this is, Alice?
This is a bribe.
누군가 공무 수행에
영향을 끼치려는 거지
Somebody is trying to influence
public policy.
근데 이거면 먹힐 거 같군
And I think it might work.
오셨군요
Hey.
경감님을 위해 조율을
좀 하고 있었습니다
I was just tuning it up for ya.
- 기타 좋은데요
- 마누라 거야
- It's a nice guitar.
- It's Karen's.
오늘 연주하실 건가요?
You're gonna play today?
때 되면 알게 될 거야
We'll see how it goes.
제가 후딱 집에 가서 제 깁슨 기타를
가져오면 재즈 연주회도 가능할 거예요
You know, I can run home and grab
my gibson and we can jam.
고등학교 때 록 밴드에 있었거든요
We used to have a rock band
back in high school.
'랜디 디셔 프로젝트'였죠
Randy Disher Project.
멋진 밴드 이름인데
어떻게 지어낸 건가?
That's a good name.
How'd you come up with that?
뭐, 제 이름인 랜디 디셔에
프로젝트를 붙인 거죠
Well, my name's Randy Disher
and then, Project.
랜디, 사실 난
재즈 연주 같은 건 못해
You know, Randy,
I don't really jam.
- 난 포크 쪽이거든
- 잘됐네요
- I'm more of an old folky kinda guy.
- That's cool.
그것도 좋은데요
제가 그냥 합창을 해도 되죠
That's cool, too.
I mean, I could just sing harmony.
멋지겠군
Good.
이야, 뭐 받으셨어요?
Whoa, hey, what'd you get?
길 아래 편에 있는
자동차 정비소에서 온 거야
This is from the body shop
down the street.
이런, 포트와인이네
난 포트와인이 싫어
Ugh, hell, it's port.
I hate port.
전 포트와인 좋아해요
I love port.
저기, 그거 집사람한테나
갖다줘야겠네
You know, I think I'll bring
it home for Karen.
사모님께서 포트와인을
좋아하세요?
What, does she likes port?
이건 쉽게 맛 들일 수
있는 게 아니거든요
It's kind of an acquired taste.
저야 포트와인이 좋지만
많은 사람들은 싫어하죠
I like port.
A lot of people don't.
랜디, 집에 갖고 갈 거라니까
Randy, I'm taking it home.
몽크 씨, 8시 반이에요
Mr. Monk, it's 8:30.
난 이미 준비됐어요
I'm ready when you are.
- 아저씨 쪽은 어때요?
- 아직까지 내 쪽은 완벽해
- How is your side looking?
- So far, my side is perfect.
왜 그러니?
What's wrong?
- 아름답나요?
- 아름답다니, 뭐가?
- Is it beautiful?
- Is what beautiful?
눈이요
Snow.
눈을 본 적이 없는 거니?
You've never seen snow?
정말 아름답단다
Oh, it's very beautiful.
똑같은 눈송이가 하나도 없지만
No two flakes are the same.
이상하게도 왠지 아름답지
But somehow it's still beautiful.
몽크 씨, 어서요
Mr. Monk, come on.
어서 가요
몽크 씨 선물은 어디 있어요?
We gotta go.
Where's your present?
복도에 있어요
Oh, it's in the hallway.
몽크 씨랑 같이 보내는 거
정말 괜찮은 거지?
Sweetie, are you sure okay
with Mr. Monk being here?
그럼요. 그거야말로
진정한 크리스마스잖아요?
Yeah, it's okay, mom.
It's what Christmas is all about, right?
- 사람들 돕기
- 그래
Helping people. / Yes.
그건 누구 거예요?
Who's that for?
트루디가 저에게
보내는 선물이에요
This one's from Trudy.
It's for me.
- 트루디가요?
- 네
- From Trudy?
- Yeah.
아내가 죽은 후 발견한 거죠
After she died, I found it.
매년 크리스마스 때
트리 밑에 두고 있어요
Every Christmas I put it
under the tree.
- 한 번도 안 열어 보셨어요?
- 응
- You never open it?
- No.
그건 뭐예요?
What's that one?
경감님께 드릴 선물이란다
내가 경감님 이름을 뽑았거든
This one's for Captain Stottlemeyer.
I picked his name.
모든 사람이 모자에서 이름을
뽑으면 그게 누구든 간에
Everybody picked a name out of a hat.
Whoever you got,
그 사람의 비밀 산타가 돼서
선물을 사 주는 거야
you're their secret Santa and
you have to buy 'em a present.
뭘 사셨나요?
What did you get him?
경감님이 좋아하실 거라고만 말해 두지
All I can tell you is that
he's gonna love it.
정말 멋진 파티가 될 테니
별로 걱정할 게 없단다
It's gonna be a great party.
I'm not completely dreading it.
바로 그 정신이에요
갈게. 문 꼭 잠그고
That's the spirit.
Okay, lock up.
좋은 꿈 꾸렴
기다리지 말고
Have a good night.
Don't wait up.
저기요
Hey.
- 네
- 스웨터 좋은데요
Hey. / Oh, nice sweater.
아, 고마워요. 보스턴 사시는 케이 고모가
손수 만들어서 보낸 거예요
Oh, thanks. It's a gift from my aunt Kay
in Boston. She knitted it herself.
우와
Wow. / Mmm hmm.
짜는 데 한 달이나 걸리셨대요
Yeah, she said it took her months.
- 절 제일 좋아하시거든요
- 정말 그런 것 같네요
- I'm her favorite nephew.
- I'm sure you are.
금방 올게요. 알았죠?
I'll be right back, okay?
안녕하세요
메리 크리스마스
Hey.
Merry Christmas.
두 분 사촌이세요?
You two cousins?
어디서 구했어요?
Where did you get that?
월 마트에서 15달러 줬어요
Walmart. 15 bucks.
아마 케이 고모가 월 마트에서
Aunt Kay probably went to Walmart
저 스웨터를 보시고 집에서
똑같이 짜셨을 거예요
and saw that sweater and went home
and knitted me the same one.
저 스웨터를 보고
영감을 얻으신 거죠
That sweater inspired this one.
여기 보면 아직도 고모님이
상표를 뗀 자국이 보여요
You can still see where
she tore the tag off.
뭐, 어떻게 생각하느냐가
중요한 거죠
It's the thought that counts.
앨리스 씨
Alice.
안녕하세요, 에이드리안
메리 크리스마스예요
Hello, Adrian.
Merry Christmas.
요즘 통 못 뵀어요
I haven't seen you around lately.
전 명절 때는
잘 안 돌아다녀요
I don't go out much
during the holidays.
혼자라 좀 우울하거든요
It's so depressing.
제가 말 안 해도 아실 거예요
앨리스도 결혼 안 했죠?
I don't have to tell you.
I mean, you're not married, eighther?
애인도 없으시잖아요
You don't have anyone.
그렇죠
That's true.
특히 우리 나이 또래가
되면 견디기 힘들죠
It's tough.
Especially for people our age.
♪ Oh holy night!
The stars are brightly shining ♪
The stars are brightly shining. ♪
♪ It is the night of our dear
Savior's birth! ♪
♪ It is the night of our dear Savior's birth! ♪
♪ Long lay the world in
sin and sorrow pining ♪
♪ Till he appeared and
the soul felt its worth ♪
♪ A thrill of hope
the weary world rejoices ♪
♪ A thrill of hope the weary world rejoices ♪
♪ For yonder breaks
a new and glorious morn! ♪
♪ Fall on your knees ♪
♪ Oh hear the angel voices ♪
♪ Oh night divine ♪
♪ Oh night when Christ was born ♪
♪ Oh night ♪
♪ Oh holy night ♪
자, 여러분 주목해 주세요
이제 자정이 거의 다 되었으니
Okay, excuse me everybody.
It's almost midnight.
비밀 산타들이 각자 자기
선물을 가져올 시간이랍니다
So it's time for all you secret Santas
to go get your presents.
경감님
Captain.
- 어, 그래
- 메리 크리스마스예요
Hey. / Merry Christmas.
오, 자네가 내
비밀 산타였구먼
Oh, you got me.
경감님 댁에 놓으라고
드리는 공기 정화기예요
It's a...it's an air purifier
for your house.
우리 집에서 냄새가 난다는 소린가?
Are you saying my house smells?
경감님 댁이
그렇단 게 아니라요
Not your house.
경감님이 사시는 것과 같은
대부분의 집에서는 가끔...
But houses like yours
sometimes get a...
왜, 있잖아요. 뭔가 시큼한... 그러니까
약간 불쾌한 냄새가...
odor that's, you know sour or
very unpleasant kind of stench of...
- 경감님 댁 말고요
- 고맙네
- Not your house.
- Thank you.
고마워, 몽크
Thank you, Monk.
- 메리 크리스마스예요
- 고마워
- Merry Christmas.
- Thank you.
자네도 메리 크리스마스
Merry Christmas to you.
자네 이베이가 뭔지 아나?
(E-Bay : 인터넷 경매 사이트)
Do you know what Ebay is?
- 이베이라... 모릅니다
- 잘됐군
Ebay, no. / Good.
제가 몽크 씨의 비밀 산타랍니다
I'm your secret Santa.
앨리스, 고마워요
메리 크리스마스
Alice, thank you.
Merry Christmas.
- 와, 재미있는 카드네요
- 그렇죠
- Oh, it's a funny card.
- Yes, it is.
느낌표가 참...
You can tell because of
the exclamation points.
뭘 받았나?
What'd you get?
이런 세상에
Oh, my god.
앨리스
Alice.
- 정말 맘에 들어요
- 잘됐어요
This I love.
Thanks.
무슨 일이세요?
Are you okay?
테리 주려고 산 선물 말인데
The present that I bought for Terry.
혹시 자네가 건드렸나?
Do you know what happened to it?
아뇨. 뭐였는데요?
No, what was it?
그냥 이만한 이발기야
A little hair trimmer thingy.
It was this big.
- 내가 직접 포장했는데
- 서류 가방 안에는 보셨어요?
- I wrapped it myself.
- Did you check your briefcase?
그럼
Yeah.
그냥 책상 위에 있는 것 중
아무거나 주지 그러세요?
Why don't you give him one
of these toys from your desk?
안 돼. 그 친구는 내 사무실에 자주 와서
여기 있던 걸 그냥 준 건 줄 알 거야
No, he's been in this office a million times.
He'd know I recycled it.
그럼 저건요?
Or what about..?
테리가 포트와인을 좋아하나?
Does he like port?
그럴걸요
I think so.
메리 크리스마스, 친구
Merry Christmas, my friend.
포트와인 좋아하나?
Like port?
- 좋아 죽죠
- 잘됐군!
Oh, I love it. / Excellent.
고마워요, 경감님
Thanks, Captain.
- 메리 크리스마스예요
- 자네도
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas to you.
테리 씨?
Terry?
테리?
Terry!
테리!
테리! 이봐
Terry! Hey.
이봐, 이봐, 테리
Hey, hey, buddy.
- 테리
Terry. / Terry.
이봐
Hey.
앰뷸런스 불러
존, 불러와
Hey, call an ambulance.
John, John, call it in.
어떻게 된 거죠?
What happened?
뭐라던가?
What did he say?
아직 예비 검시 결과입니다
It's still preliminary.
뭐라고 했느냐니까, 랜디?
What did he say, Randy?
스트리키닌 같은
독성 신경 흥분제의 일종이래요
Poison.
Some kind of strychnine.
소량으로도 충분하며
누구나 만들 수 있는 것이죠
Some gone effective.
Anybody could've made it.
맛도 못 느꼈던 걸까?
Couldn't he have tasted it?
- 포트와인은 맛이 강한 술이지 않나요?
- 정말 독한 와인이죠
- Port's pretty heavy drink, isn't it?
- It's really strong.
그 맛 때문에 독극물 맛을
느낄 수 없었을 거예요
He wouldn't taste it in that.
경감님, 시체를 가져가야 한다는데요
Captain, they need the body.
날 노린 거였어
This was meant for me.
하나님의 은총 덕에 사셨어요
Well, there weren't for the grace of god.
내가 죽어야 했다니까
This was meant for me.
하나님의 은총이라니...
A grace of god.
경감님
Captain.
정말 유감이에요
I'm really so sorry.
테리 씨 나이가 38세였죠?
결혼은 했었나요?
He was only 38 years old, right?
Was he married?
- 아뇨. 별거 중인 걸로 알고 있어요
- 아냐
- Nah, I think they were separated.
- No.
방금 제니와 통화했는데
다시 합쳤더군
They're back together.
I just talked to Jenny.
쌍둥이인 두 딸이 있고
They got two little girls.
Twins.
병과 함께 온 거라곤
카드뿐이네요 / 네
Just a card.
It came with the bottle. / Yeah.
그리고 아무도 가져온
사람을 못 봤고요?
And nobody saw who delivered it?
접수처에 있었어요
It was sitting at the front desk.
- 누구든지 두고 갈 수 있죠
- 정말 면목이 없네요
- Anybody could've dropped it off there.
- I'm so sorry.
비밀 산타 행사를 하기로
한 건 제 생각이었어요
It was my idea for the gift exchange,
secret Santa, I just..
앨리스, 자책하지 마세요
Alice, you can't blame yourself.
방금 차량 정비소 사장인
존 다실바를 깨워서 얘기해 봤는데
Well, I just woke up John DaSilva.
He owns the body shop.
그쪽에선 선물이나 주류를
보낸 적이 없다고 했습니다
He says they never sent
gifts or liqouor.
도와주겠다고 나섰지만
큰 도움은 안 될 것 같습니다
He offered to come down and
take a poly but it feels like a dead end.
누가 보냈든 간에 경감님이
그곳 손님인 걸 알고 있었어요
Whoever sent it knew you
did business with them.
그것으로 범인을 좁혀
볼 수 있지 않을까요?
That narrows it down, right?
샌프란시스코 경찰 독점 공급 업체
Exclusive parts supplier for the SFPD.
광고에 전부 나와 있는 사실이라
누구든 알 수 있었을 겁니다
It's in all their ads.
Anybody could've seen it.
좋아. 수사를 시작합시다
Okay, let's get to it.
제가 용의자를 다섯으로
좁혀 놨습니다
I've narrowed it down to
5 possible suspects.
원한이 있거나
경감님이 체포하신...
People who may have had a grudge,
people you arrested..
범인은 프랭크 프레이거야
It was Frank Prager.
네. 프랭크는 1순위로
명단에 올렸습니다
Yes, sir, Frank's on the list.
He's number one.
프레이거가 누구죠?
Who's Prager?
1년 전, 경감님이 마이크 프레이거라는
은행털이를 사살했죠
A year ago, captain shot and killed
a bank robber named Mike Prager.
프랭크는 그의 형입니다
Frank's his brother.
몇 달 전, 보복을 하려고 했죠
A few months ago,
tried to settle the score.
주차장에서 내 앞에 나타나
총을 다섯 발 쐈지만 못 맞췄지
He came at me in a parking lot.
He got off five rounds and he missed.
- 도망쳤나요?
- 사라졌어요
- Got away?
- Disappeared.
이번에도 복수에 실패한 것 같군요
And it looks like he missed again.
자, 각자 한 명씩 맡는 건 어때요?
All right, Why don't we each take a name?
경위, 시간 낭비일세
프랭크 프레이거가 확실해
Lieutenant, you're wasting your time.
I'm telling you it's Frank Prager.
좋습니다. 이건 어떻습니까?
All right.
How about this?
팀을 둘로 나누는 건 어떨까요?
How about we split up into
two teams?
경감님 팀이 프레이거를 맡고
저희 팀은 나머지를 맡는 겁니다
Your team gets Prager and
my team will take the rest of the list.
좋아요
Okay.
어디 보자
Let's see.
뭐 하고 있나?
What are you doing?
제 팀원을 고르는 겁니다
I'm picking my team.
전...
I'll take...
몽크를 뽑겠습니다
I'll take Monk.
안 돼. 몽크는 내가 데려가겠네
No, I'll take Monk.
알겠습니다
Okay.
나탈리 씨를 뽑겠습니다
I'll take Natalie.
안 돼요. 줄리가 집에서
기다리고 있거든요
Oh, I can't.
Julie's waiting for me at home.
좋아요
Fine.
음, 그럼 전...
Um, I'll take...
자넨 로빈스와 가게
You'll take Robins.
정오에 여기서 다시 보자고
Meet us back here at noon.
전 로빈스와 가겠습니다
I'll take Robins.
가자고
Let's go.
넉 달 전, 화요일 밤이었어
Four months ago, it was
a Tuesday night.
난 새벽 두 시에
술집에서 나왔고
I came out of the bar, 2 a.m.
동료가 차 열쇠를 가져가서
난 집까지 걸어가려고 했지
They took my keys so I'm
walking home.
혼자였고
I was alone.
아주 많이 취해 있었지
I was pretty toasted.
가로등이 켜져 있어서
주변을 볼 수 있었다네
That street light was on,
'cuz I could still see.
그런데 놈이 기다리고 있었어
그게...
And he was waiting.
He was by...
이쪽에 있던 커다란
검정 밴 뒤에 있었어
There was a big black van here.
He waiting behind it.
아마 밤새 날 기다렸을 거야
Must've been here all night.
놈이 걸어 나왔고
He steps out.
난 지금 자네가
서 있는 곳에 있었고
I'm standing right about where
you are now.
놈을 본 순간 바로 알아차렸지
바로 프랭크 프레이거였어
I knew who it was right away.
It was Frank Prager
날 죽이고 싶어 하는 마음을
놈의 눈을 보고 알 수 있었지
and he wanted me dead.
I could see it in his eyes.
놈은 글록17을 내 머리를 향해
겨눈 후 다섯 발을 쐈지
He aims Glock 17
to my head, caps off 5 rounds.
그러곤...
And then..
사라져 버렸지
And then he disappeared.
어젯밤까지 말이야
Until last night.
불과 4미터 거리에
He was only 12 feet away.
가로등을 등지고 있었다면
맞추기 힘든 상황이 아닌데요
With the street light behind him,
it's not a hard shot.
- 특수 부대 베테랑이었다면서요?
- 맞아
You said he was a veteran
special ops? / Yeah.
놈도 나만큼 취했었나 보지
Maybe he was as toasted as me.
기적이었을지도 모르고
Or maybe it was a miracle.
아마 그랬던 것 같네요
Maybe it was.
그런데 탄흔을
그대로 남겨 두었네요
And they just left the bullet holes there.
아마 장삿속에 그랬을 거야
Well, it's probably good for business
at this place.
뭔가 신비감을 주잖아
It adds to the mystique.
마구잡이로 쏜 게 아니에요
This pattern does not look random.
둘-하나-둘이잖아요
2-1-2
글록17이면 스무 발은
쏠 수 있었을 텐데
He had a Glock 17.
He could've fired 20 rounds.
그 사람은 딱 다섯 발만 쐈어요
둘-하나-둘씩요
He only squeezed off 5.
2-1-2.
몽크, 이건 중요한 게 아냐
Monk.
It doesn't matter.
놈은 총으로 안 되니까
독극물을 시도한 거라고
He's given up on guns.
They guy's graduated to strychnine.
- 수법이 다른데요
- 놈은 특수 부대 출신이라고
- It's a different M.O.
- He's special ops, remember?
그들은 100가지나 되는 살해 방법을
알고 있는 자들이야
Those guys know a hundred
different ways to kill somebody.
프랭크는 날 죽이려 했어
Prager wants me dead.
놈의 동생을 쏜 사람이 나거든
I'm the guy that shot his brother.
그 사람, 결혼해서 딸도 있죠?
He's married, right?
With a daughter.
그래. 일곱 살 난
귀여운 아이가 있어
Yeah, cute kid, 7 years old.
서로 연락하지 않을까요?
Is he in touch with them?
몇 주 전에 그 집 밖에서
잠복근무를 했었는데
Well, we staked out the house
for a couple of weeks,
전화도 없었고
나타난 적도 없었어
but he never called or showed his face.
한번 조사해 보죠. 어쩌면...
크리스마스라 집에 있을 수 있잖아요
Well, let's check it out.
Maybe..maybe he's home for Christmas.
이봐, 몽크
난 그 집 근처에 갈 수 없어
Look, Monk.
I can't go near the place.
내가 귀찮게 한다고 프랭크의 아내가
날 상대로 민원을 제기했거든
The wife filed a complaint against me,
said that I had been harrassing her.
왜 그랬대요?
Why would she say that?
아마 내가 귀찮게 해서 그랬을걸
Probably because I have been
harrassing her.
- 왜요?
- 부인이 자네를 본 적은 없잖아
- What?
- She's never seen you.
얼마나 오래 걸려요?
How much longer?
나탈리, 잠복근무란 건 말이죠
Natalie, this is stake-out.
얼마나 걸릴지 모르는 거예요
You never know how long.
그게 잠복근무의 묘미죠
That's what makes a stake-out
so much fun.
스무고개 할래요?
Oh, you wanna play 20 questions?
- 좋죠
- 좋아요. 먼저 하세요
Sure. / Okay.
Right, you can go first.
살아 있든 죽었든
아무나 생각해 봐요
You have to think of somebody,
anybody, living or dead.
네, 생각했어요
Okay, I got it.
트루디예요?
Is it Trudy?
- 성이 뭔데요?
- 당신 아내 트루디 몽크요
- Trudy who?
- Trudy Monk, your wife.
네, 고맙네요
Yes, thank you.
재밌었어요
That was fun.
몽크 씨, 크리스마스에
뭘 받고 싶어요?
So, Mr. Monk, what do you want
for Christmas?
기적요
A miracle.
네. 나도 그게 필요해요
Yeah.
I could use one of those.
줄리는 눈이 안 온다면서
샌프란시스코를 싫어해요
Julie hates it here because
it never snows.
매년 화이트 크리스마스가
되기를 기도하죠
She's been praying for this
white Christmas.
그러게요. 지난 9년간
샌프란시스코엔 눈이 안 왔죠
Well, it hasn't snowed in
San Fransisco in 9 years.
마지막으로 눈이 온 건
트루디가 숨진 날이었으니까요
The last time it snowed
was the day Trudy died.
세상에, 더 이상 못 참겠어요
그냥 가서 문을 두드려 봐요
Oh, my god, I can't stand it.
Let's just go up there and knock on the door.
그리고 뭐라고 그럴 건데요?
And say what?
♪ Silent night, holy night ♪
♪ All is calm, all is bright ♪
♪ Round yon virgin mother and Child ♪
- 촛농이 흘러요
- 원래 그런 거예요
- It's dripping.
- It's suppposed to drip.
♪ Holy Infant, so tender and mild ♪
♪ Sleep in heavenly peace ♪
앗, 뜨거!
Ouch.
메리 크리스마스예요
Merry Christmas.
성가를 부르는 사람들은 항상 봐 왔는데
보통 단체로 다니지 않나요?
Yeah, we get carolers all the time.
Ususally, there's whole group.
- 맞아요
- 네
Right. / Yeah.
- 저희도 일행이 있었죠
- 처음엔 사람이 많았죠
- We had a group.
- We started with a big crowd.
그러다 저흰...
And then we had..
어쩌다 보니 일행을 놓쳤고
이렇게 따로 다니게 됐어요
But then we lost them somehow
and then dropped out.
맞아요. 우릴 두고 가더라고요
Yeah, they just left.
- 어쩌다가요?
- 컨셉의 차이랄까요
- What happened?
- Creative differences.
그 사람들은 종교적인
것을 싫어하더라고요
They really weren't comfortable
with the religious material.
전혀 다른 것을 원했어요
Just wanted to a whole..
whole different thing.
라스베가스 스타일을
원했지만 저흰 아니었죠
Other.. like a Vegas style.
We were not..
- 맞아요
- 전혀 취향이 아니죠
No. / Not into it.
- 그래도 그 사람들의 안녕을 빌어요
- 맞아요
- But we wish them well.
- Yeah.
- 화장실 좀 쓸 수 있을까요?
- 흥행 사업이라는 게 원래 좀...
- Can I use your bathroom?
- Show business is a ...
그럼요. 들어오세요
Yeah, sure.
Come on in.
네가 도리니?
Are you Dory?
어떻게 아셨어요?
How did you know?
아, 네 아빠가 말해 주셨단다
Um, well, your daddy told me.
우리 아빠를 아세요?
Do you know my daddy?
그렇다고 볼 수 있지
In a way, yeah.
난 네 아빠를 찾고 있는데
어디 계시는지 아니?
I've been looking for him.
Do you know where he is?
쉿, 비밀이에요
Sshh.
It's a secret.
비밀이라, 알았다
아무에게도 말 안 하마
It's a secret, okay.
I won't tell anybody.
뭐 하시는 거죠?
What are you doing?
전 그냥...
I was just...
당신들 경찰인가요?
Are you a cop?
- 저기.. 사실은요
- 도리, 방으로 가거라
- Okay, look, here's the thing.
- Dory, go to your room.
나가 주세요
내 집에서 나가요
I want you out.
Just get out of my house.
이미 우리 가족에게
충분한 고통을 줬잖아요
Haven't you people done enough
to this family?
일이 잘 풀렸네요
That went well.
잠깐만요. 계획은 있는 거예요?
Okay, hold it, hold it.
Do we have a plan?
네? 아뇨. 하지만 전 꼭 저 아이와
다시 얘기를 해 봐야겠어요
What? No, I need to talk to
the little girl again.
잠깐이면 돼요
저 아이는 분명 뭔가를 알고 있어요
Just for a minute.
She knows something, I'm telling you.
대체 왜 이리 사람들이 많아요?
Who are all these people?
이 사람들은 진정한 크리스마스의
의미를 잊었나 봐요
These folks have forgotten
the true meaning of Christmas.
- 그래요? 그게 뭔데요?
- 절 가만히 내버려 두는 거죠
- Yeah? Which is what?
- Which is leaving me alone.
전 이 모든 게 다 좋아요
Well, I love it.
I love everything about it.
사람들이며 쇼핑에 장식들까지...
The crowd, the shopping,
the decorations.
그게 불쾌한 느낌을 줘도
괜찮나 보죠?
The fact that it's horrible
doesn't bother you?
- 세상에, 이 사람 아직도 여기 있네요
- 누가 여기 있다는 거예요?
My gosh, I can't believe
he's still here.
Who's here? / Mr. Preston.
I used to work here.
프리스톤 씨요
여기서 일한 적이 있거든요
잠깐만요
대체 가졌던 직업이 몇 개예요?
Wait a minute.
How many jobs have you had?
고등학교 졸업 후
여름에 잠깐 했었어요
It was just after high school.
It was a summer thing.
안내 데스크에서 3주
정도밖에 못 했어요
I worked at the information booth,
but it only lasted for 3 weeks.
어쩌다가요?
What happened?
프리스톤 씨가 절 좀
많이 좋아했었거든요
Mr. Preston liked me, a lot,
a little too much.
전 그런 문제는 없었는데
Oh, I never had that problem.
20분 후면 산타가 돌아옵니다
SANTA WILL RETURN
IN 20 MINUTES.
- 금방 돌아올게요
- 어디 가요?
- I'll be right back.
- Where are you going?
프리스톤 씨를 찾으러요
나한테 진 빚이 있거든요
I'm gonna go find Mr. Preston.
He owes me a favor.
무슨 빚인데요?
What kind of favor?
산타 할아버지
많이 기다렸죠?
Who's waiting to see Santa Claus?
와아!
Yeah.
여러분은 운이
참 좋아요
Well, you're in luck.
방금 누가 북극에서
날아왔게요?
Because guess who just landed
straight from the North Pole?
산타클로스요!
Santa Claus!
와아!
Yay!
호, 호, 호
Ho, ho, ho.
와아!
Yay!
쉿! 자, 여러분 잘 들어요
Ssh. Okay, everybody listen up.
Okay?
산타 할아버지와 만날 때에 대한
새로운 규칙이 생겼어요
We have some new rules
here in Santa's workshop.
산타 할아버지 무릎에 앉기 전에
Before anybody can sit on Santa's lap,
모두 마술 티슈를 써서
꼭 손을 닦아야 해요
you have to use these magic wipes
and wipe your hand.
와, 닦는 건 재밌어요
Yay, wiping is fun.
그리고 아무도 산타 할아버지의
얼굴을 건드리면 안 돼요
And no touching Santa's face.
또 산타를 향해 숨을 쉬면 안 되고요
And try not to breathe on Santa.
명심하세요. 산타도 항상
기분이 좋지만은 않다는걸요
Remember, Santa isn't always jolly.
가끔은 산타 할아버지도
조금 울적할 때가 있답니다
Sometimes Santa's a little bit sad.
알았죠?
누가 먼저 갈까요?
Okay?
Who's first?
아니, 아니, 그냥...
No, no, no, just..
거기 서 있어라
Just stand over there.
그동안 착한 소년이었니?
Have you been a good boy?
- 그랬니?
- 몽크 씨, 무릎에 앉혀요
Have you? / Mr. Monk, he's gotta
sit on your lap. You're Santa Claus.
- 싫어요
- 꼭 무릎에 앉아야 해요, 자요
- I don't think so.
- He has to sit on your lap. Here.
- 올라타세요
- 안 돼, 안 돼
Jump up. / No, no, no.
- 돼
- 너무 가깝잖니
Yep. / That's too close.
좋아. 무릎에만 타거라
무릎에만. 그래 좀 더 멀리
All right, just on the knee.
On the knee there, a little further.
좀 더 멀리 앉거라
얘가 몸부림쳐요
A little further.
He's squirming.
산타는 몸부림치는
사람을 안 좋아한단다
Santa doesn't like the squirmers.
사랑해요, 산타 할아버지
I love you, Santa.
얘가... 얘가 뭐 하는 거죠?
What is she..
What is she doing?
- 키스해 달래요
- 안 돼요
- She wants a kiss.
- No.
안 돼, 안 돼. 미안하다
자, 끝났다
No, no, sorry.
No. Good. You're done.
됐다. 거기까지
이만 가 봐라
Okay, that's it.
You're done.
잠깐만요. 목록을 만들었어요
Wait, but I made a list.
잘했구나. 편지로 보내렴
알았지? 자, 이만 끝
Yeah, good, mail it to me, okay?
You're done.
제가 원하는 크리스마스 선물은
돌 광택기 세트예요
All I want for Christmas
is a rock polishing kit.
돌 광택기 세트라고?
Rock polishing kit?
네가 제일 착한 아이구나
You're Santa's favorite.
- 이름이 뭐니?
- 트루디요
- What's your name?
- Trudy.
괜찮으세요?
Are you okay?
단지 그냥...
It's just that..
내 아내 이름이 트루디였단다
My wife's name was Trudy.
자동차 폭탄 사고로 죽었지
She was killed by a car bomb.
폭탄이 조수석 아래에 있었는데
It was under the passenger seat.
차가 완전히 폭발했단다
The whole car exploded.
자, 너도 이만 끝
이제 가거라. 호, 호, 호
Okay, you're done.
You're done, ho, ho
어서 가거라
Let's go.
그래, 이름은 뭐니?
And what's your name?
- 도리요
- 도리라, 예쁜 이름이구나
Dory. / Dory, that's a pretty name.
난 도리가 크리스마스에
무엇을 원하는지 알지
I bet I know what you want
for Christmas.
아빠가 집에 오시길 바라지
You want your daddy to come home.
나도 돕고 싶지만
문제가 있단다
And I wanna help you, but
I have a problem.
네 아빠를 찾을 수가 없더구나
아빠가 어디 계시는지 아니?
I just can't find him.
Do you know where he is?
교회에 계세요
In a church.
교회에 살고 계시는 거니?
He lives in a church?
- 천사 셋이 문밖에 있는 곳이에요
- 천사 셋이라
- With the 3 ladies out front.
- 3 ladies.
아빠
Daddy.
저자예요
That's him.
저자가 프레이거예요
That's Prager.
- 나탈리
- 프랭크, 경찰이에요!
Natalie. / Frank, they're cops.
이상 무
Clear.
몽크 말이 맞았습니다
놈은 여기 있습니다
Monk was right.
He's in there.
- 천사 셋이 밖에 있는 곳은 여기뿐이지
- 그렇습니다
Three ladies out front,
that was all we needed. / Yes, sir.
9월부터 이곳 지하 방에서
He's been living in there
since September.
브래드 엘리엇이란 이름으로
생활해 왔었답니다
Been in the room in the basement.
He's going by the name Brad Elliot.
놈의 가명이 뭔지는
전혀 관심 없어
I don't give a rat's ass
what he calls himself.
가서 놈을 잡자고
Let's go get him.
뒤쪽을 맡게나. 내 신호에 맞춰서
들어간다고 저격수에게 전하고
Cover the back. Tell the snipers
we're going in on my signal.
잠깐만요
Wait, wait.
안에 수녀가 있는데
There's a nun in there.
나오려고 하지 않아요
She won't leave.
- 수녀가?
- 좋은 분 같았습니다
- A nun?
- Sounded nice.
진정 수녀다우신 분이셨는데...
She had a nun-y quality.
뭐라던가, 랜디?
What did she want, Randy?
경감님과 얘기를 하고 싶답니다
She just wants to talk to you.
경감님이 범인을 거칠게
다룰까 봐 걱정하고 있어요
She's afraid you're gonna
rough him up.
대기하고 있어 봐
Stand down.
대기하라
아니, 가만히 있어
No, no, no, stay put.
현재 위치를 사수하라
Hold your positions.
- 대기하고 있어
- 현재 위치를 사수하라
- Stand down.
- Hold your positions.
- 스토틀마이어 경감님
- 네
Captain Stottlemeyer. / Yeah.
전 헤더 수녀입니다
I'm sister Heather.
안녕하세요, 수녀님
Hi, sister.
- 제가 여기 왜 온 건지 아시죠?
- 네
- You know why I'm here, right?
- Yes.
그는 여기 있어요
이곳 성역에 있지요
He's here.
He's in the sanctuary.
아주 겁을 먹고 있어요
He's very frightened.
그가 당신을 죽이려
했다고 생각하세요?
You think he tried to murder you?
네, 그렇습니다
Yes, ma'am, I do.
정말 확신을 갖고 계시는군요
You obviously have very strong
feelings about this.
두말하면...
You got that..
네, 그렇습니다
Yes, I do.
전 브래드 씨가 학대 받지
않길 바랄 뿐이에요
I just wanna make sure
that Brad isn't mistreated.
그 사람 이름은 브래드가 아닙니다
Brad's not his name.
맞아요
You're right.
전 그의 본명을 모릅니다
I don't know his real name.
하지만 전 그 사람을 알아요
But I know the man.
그는 우리의 봉사 활동에
참여해 왔습니다
He's been working in our
outreach program.
매일 밤 배고픈 사람이나
노숙자들에게 음식을 대접했어요
He's been feeding the hungry
and homeless every night.
그들이 여기까지 못 올 만큼 지쳐 있으면
직접 음식을 가져다줬어요
When they're too tired to come here,
he brings the food to them.
양심의 가책 때문이었나 보죠
Well, maybe he has a guilty conscience.
어떤 이유의 양심이든
요즘 세상엔 보기 힘들죠
Well, any conscience at all
is a rare thing these days.
원하시는 게 뭐죠, 경감님?
What do you want, Captain?
전 정의를 원합니다
I want justice.
하지만 그는 당신이 다른 것을
원할까 봐 걱정하고 있어요
Well, he's afraid that you want
something else.
경감님과 다른 경찰관들이 원하는 게...
He's afraid you and the other
policemen want...
복수 말씀이군요
Revenge.
제 아버지께선 중요한
가르침을 주셨는데
My father wants taught me
an important lesson.
용서만큼 완벽한
복수는 없다고 하셨죠
There's no revenge so complete
as forgiveness.
- 하느님 말씀이시군요
- 경감님의 아버지시기도 하죠
- Your father.
- He's your father too.
알겠습니다. 절대로 놈을
해치지 않겠다고 약속드리죠
Okay, look, I promise you
that I will not hurt him.
좋습니다
Okay.
프랭크, 교회 옆엔
진료소가 있던데
Frank, there's a clinic
next to the church.
그곳엔 약품과 화학 물질들이 있죠
They have drugs, they have chemicals.
그 보관 창고에 들어간 적이 있습니까?
Did you have access to the storage room?
제게 열쇠 같은 건 없었지만
Uh huh. I mean,
I didn't have key or anything,
마음만 먹었다면
쉽게 들어갔겠죠
but it would've been easy
enough to break in.
전 누구도 독살하지 않았어요
전 살인자가 아닙니다
I didn't poison anybody.
I'm not a killer.
오, 그래. 그럼 넉 달 전 주차장에서
우리가 한 데이트는 뭐였지?
Oh, right. What about our last date
in the parking lot 4 months ago?
경감님을 죽이려 한 게 아니었어요
I wasn't trying to kill you.
웃기는 소리 마
You can't be serious.
좋습니다
All right.
그러려고도 생각했지만
I thought about it.
막상 닥치니 그럴 수 없더군요
When I got there, I couldn't.
제 동생처럼 되기가 싫었습니다
I didn't want to become my brother.
마지막 순간에, 전 메시지를
남기기로 마음먹었습니다
The last minute, I decided to
send you a message.
메시지라고?
A message?
오, 세상에
Oh, my god.
경감님, 그 탄흔 말이에요
Captain, the pattern.
그건 마이클의 'M'을
뜻하는 거였어요
It was M.
M for Michael
그래요. 'M'이었어요
Yeah.
It was an M.
어떻게 그걸 놓칠 수 있어요?
How could you miss it?
허, 내가 어떻게 그게 'M'이란 걸
알 수 있었겠나?
Well, how was I supposed
to know that was the letter M?
이 사람은 자유 진영에서
최고 가는 탐정인데
This guy's the best detective
in the free world.
그런 그도 그게
'M'인 줄 몰랐다고
He didn't know that was an M.
왜, 그냥 남들처럼
스프레이를 뿌리지 그랬어?
What, you couldn't use
a spray can like everyvody else?
세상에, 메시지라니
Oh, for god's sake, a message.
난 단지 경감님이 한 짓을
상기시켜 주고 싶었을 뿐이오
I just wanted you to think about
what you did.
마이클은 잘못된 길에 들어섰을 뿐
착한 녀석이었다고요
Michael was a good kid
who got screwed up.
잠깐, 내가 자네 동생 일을
잊었다고 생각하나?
Wait, you think I don't think
about your brother?
난 빌어먹게도 매일 같이
자네 동생에 대해 생각해
I think about your brother
every damn day of my life.
녀석 아니었으면
내가 죽었을 거야
It was him or me.
그리고 아직도 기분이
찜찜하단 말이야
And it still eats me up.
벽에 새겨진 'M'자를 안 봐도
그 일을 생생하게 기억하고 있어
I don't need an M on a wall
to remember something like that.
그냥 잊어버릴 경찰은 없다고
No cop does.
데리고 나가
Get him out of here.
갑시다
Let's go.
세상에, 경감님
이거 읽어보세요
God, Captain, you gotta read this.
이건 저 사람이 교회에
있을 때 쓴 일기장이에요
This is from the journal he kept
while he was in that church.
경감님께 한 행동에 대해 괴로워했어요
이 부분을 보세요
He feels terrible about what he did.
Look at this one part.
- 눈물이 날 정도예요
- 경감님은 볼 수 없어요
- It made me cry.
- He can't see it.
네. 알아요, 나탈리
그자는 범인이 아니에요
Yeah, I know, Natalie.
He's not the guy, all right?
자, 다음으로 넘어가죠, 랜디
Okay, moving on, Lieutenant,
범행 동기를 가진 용의자가
네 명이 더 있다고 했지?
you said there were 4 other
suspects who might've had a motive.
사실, 한계에 부딪혔습니다
Actually, we struck out.
한 명은 사망했고, 한 명은 병원에 있고
나머지 둘은 감옥에 있습니다
One's deceased, one's in a hospital
and two are back in prison.
그럼 프랭크 프레이거도 아니고
명단에 있는 그 누구도 아니라면
Okay. So it wasn't Frank Prager.
It's nobody on your list.
누가 나에게 와인을 보낸 거지?
Who sent me that bottle of wine?
놈들이 다시 시도할까요?
And will they try again?
그러니까 경감님을 죽이려고요
To kill you, I mean.
무슨 말인지 나도 알아, 경위
I know what you mean, Lieutenant.
어디 보자
잘 어울리네요
Let's see.
It looks good.
아저씨도 하나 달아요
You need one, too.
자, 이건 몽크 아저씨가
주시는 선물이란다
Okay, this is from Mr. Monk.
안 주셔도 되는데요
You didn't have to get me anything.
고맙습니다
Thanks.
찢지 말아...
Don't tear..
- 구급상자네요
- 올해 최고의 인기 선물이지
- First Aid kit.
- That is the hot gift this year.
이건 구급 상자계의 캐딜락이야
It's the Cadillac of first aid kits.
100피트 길이의 거즈
다섯 가지 연고와 지혈대
I'm talking about 100 feed of gauze,
5 different ointments, and a tourniquet.
- 게다가 이 지혈대는 말이지...
- 자, 거기까지. 나중에 보시고
- Now that tourniquet...
- Okay, that's great.
We're gonna look at that later,
우리가 준비한 선물 먼저 받으세요
because this is from both of us.
조심하세요
깨지기 쉬운 거니까요
Be careful, those are fragile.
살아있는 생물이네요
It's alive.
It's a living thing.
이거 죽는 거죠?
Is it gonna die?
뭐, 아주 아주 아주 나중에요
Well, not for a long long long time.
- 어쨌든 결국 죽을 거잖아요
- 친구예요
- But it'll die eventually.
- It's a friend.
- 같이 살 꼬마 친구라고요
- 죽어가는 친구겠죠
- It's a little friend to keep you company.
- A dying friend.
봐요. 안절부절 못하면서
돌고 있어요
Look at it.
It's just twitching, it's turning.
왼쪽으로 가다가
오른쪽으로 헤엄치잖아요
Left, then it swims right.
지그재그로 움직이고 있는데
안 그러게 훈련시킬 수 있을까요?
It's zigzaging.
Can we train it?
그럼요. 시계 방향으로
헤엄치게 할 수 있어요
Yeah, we can train it.
To swim clockwise.
어떻게 먹이를 주는지 보여 드릴게요
And I can show you how to feed this.
잠깐만. 기다려 봐
Okay, wait.
Stay there.
- 괜찮아요
- 내가 치워 줄게
- It's okay.
- I'll get it.
- 괜찮다니까요
- 나한테 새 빗자루가 생겼거든
- It's okay.
- My new broom.
잠깐만 기다려 봐
Just wait.
- 경감님
- 메리 크리스마스, 앨리스
Captain. / Merry Christmas Alice.
들어가도 될까?
May we come in?
무슨 일이시죠?
So what's going on?
크리스마스 파티 때 누가 날 죽이려
했는지 몽크가 알아낸 것 같네
Monk thinks that he knows who
tried to kill me during the Christmas party.
프랭크 프레이거라고 들었는데요
I heard it was Frank Prager.
아니, 프레이거가 아니었어
No, it wasn't Prager.
사실 그 누구도 아니었지
In fact, it wasn't anybody.
아무도 경감님을 죽이려 하지 않았어요
그건 단지 우릴 혼란에 빠뜨린 장치였죠
Nobody tried to kill the captain.
That was a trick to throw us off track.
목표는 테리 체이슨 경사였어요
Terry Chasen was the target.
애초부터요
From the beginning.
앨리스, 우린 테리와 당신이
사귀었다는 걸 알아요
Alice, we know you and Terry
were involved.
전화 통화 기록과
카드 명세서를 확보했어요
We've got phone records,
credit cards.
- 약 6개월간이었더군요
- 7개월
You were together for
about 6 months. / 7.
7개월간이었어요
7 months.
테리가 아내에게
돌아갔다고 해서 그를 죽인 건가?
Was it because he went back to his wife?
That's why you killed him?
앨리스
Alice.
우린 당신이 어떻게
했는지 알아요
We know how you did it.
크리스마스 선물 교환은
당신의 아이디어였기에
The Christmas gift exchange
was your idea.
경감님이 테리의 이름을
뽑게 하기는 쉬웠을 거예요
It was easy to make sure that
the captain picked Terry's name.
그래. 나도 기억해
내가 마지막으로 남은 걸 뽑았지
Yeah, I remember. I was the last one to
choose and there was one name left.
파티가 있던 날, 당신은 독이 든
와인을 경찰서에 갖고 왔죠
The day of the party, you brought
poisoned bottle into the office.
그걸 접수처에 놔두었고
You dropped it off at the front desk.
그 와인은 경감님
앞으로 되어 있었죠
It was addressed to Captain Stottlemeyer.
그리고 자넨 내가 포트와인을
싫어하는 걸 알고 있었지
And you know I don't drink port.
그 후 어느 시점에 이르러
아마도 파티 중이었겠죠
And at some point,
probably during the party,
당신은 경감님의
사무실에 몰래 들어가
you snuck into the captain's office
and you stole the gift
경감님이 테리에게
주려고 산 선물을 훔쳤어요
that he had brought in for Terry.
그리곤 경감님이 선물을 못 찾자
와인을 대신 선물하라고 제안했죠
And the captain couldn't find it,
you suggested replacing it with the bottle.
독이 든 병을요
The poisoned bottle.
정말 마술사들이 하는
교묘한 트릭처럼
It was like a magician doing
sleight of hand.
모두의 시선을
다른 곳으로 돌린 거였죠
You had everybody looking
the wrong way.
정말 영리한 계획이었어요
It was brilliant.
실례할게요
Excuse me.
앨리스
Alice.
독은 어디에 있지?
Where's the poison?
자네도 알겠지만 버려도
우린 흔적을 찾을 수 있어
You know, if you threw it away,
we'll find traces of it.
잘 알잖나
You know that.
지하실에 있어요
It's in the basement.
어떻게 아셨죠?
How did you know?
나탈리
Natalie.
이건 앨리스가 빗자루를 주면서
같이 준 카드와 봉투예요
This is the card and the enveloppe.
It came with the whisk broom
참고로 아주 잘 쓰고 있어요
정말 환상적이에요
which by the way I've been using.
It really is fantastic.
아무튼 카드가 너무 커서
But the card is a little too big.
보시다시피 접어야 했죠
See, you had to fold it over.
독이 든 병에 있던
이 카드는 너무 작았고요
This card came with the poisoned bottle.
It's too small.
앨리스, 당신은
카드를 혼동한 거였어요
Alice, you mixed them up.
혼동을 하다니...
I mixed them up.
평소의 난 아주 정돈을
잘하는데 말이죠
And I'm usually so organized.
난...
I couldn't...
그저 그이 없이 살 수가 없었어요
I just couldn't live without him.
내가 맡지
I got it.
고맙네
Thanks.
내가 검사와 얘기해 봤는데
자네에게 형량 협상안을 제시할 걸세
I talked to the DA.
She's gonna offer you a deal.
경찰 폭행 혐의로
최소 8개월형으로 말일세
8 months plus time served
on the assault.
생각해 보게
Think about it.
다시 돌아온 후에
결정해도 된다네
And you can decide
when you get back.
저보고 어디로 가라는 건데요?
Where am I going?
무보석으로 이틀간 방면될 걸세
You are released on your own
recognizance for two days.
내 판단하에 이러는 거니
Now, I'm responsible for you.
내가 후회하지 않게 해 주게나
So don't make me regret it.
집으로 가게
Go home.
궁금하지도 않아요?
Aren't you curious?
네
No.
모르는 채로 있는 게 좋아요
I love not knowing.
세상에, 이리 와 보세요
Oh, my god.
Come on.
줄리, 무슨 일이니?
Julie, sweetie, what is it?
화이트 크리스마스네
화이트 크리스마스야, 야호!
It's a white Christmas.
It's your white Christmas. Yay.
카메라 가져올게요
I'm gonna go get my camera.
난 코트 가져와야겠다
I'm getting my coat.
괜찮은 거죠?
You okay?
메리 크리스마스예요, 몽크 씨
Merry Christmas, Mr. Monk.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)